[
    {
        "question": "Which is INCORRECT about File Control Block (FCB)?",
        "answer": "It is a data structure storing file data\nOS needs a FCB to access a file"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the BEST goal of stripping in Redundant Array of Inexpensive Disks (RAID)",
        "answer": "To increase the IO speed"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the BEST goal of mirroring in Redundant Array of Inexpensive Disks (RAID)",
        "answer": "To recover data of a file if a disk crashed"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the most correct about parity blocks?",
        "answer": "Used to recover data efficiently, similar to mirroring"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is INCORRECT about hard disk?",
        "answer": "Transfer rate is the most significant factor for disk scheduling algorithms"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider a stable storage system, suppose the crash occurs before writing the first copy. Which is correct about the read protocol to recover the data?",
        "answer": "The two copies of old data are intact, so no need to do anything"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many disks can be broken without losing data in the RAID level 1",
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is correct about mirroring data among multiple disks",
        "answer": "Increase the I/O bandwidth"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the main reason of stripping data among multiple disks",
        "answer": "Increase data volume"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the reason why a number of sectors in each cylinder is unused?",
        "answer": "To be used to recover bad sectors"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the reason why the sector numbers of different cylinders are not the same?",
        "answer": "To reduce waiting time"
    },
    {
        "question": "Suppose a file has access mode 664. Which is correct?",
        "answer": "Any user can read the file"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a correct description of a directory?",
        "answer": "A directory is actually a file containing partial information about its files"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is incorrect about VFS?",
        "answer": "VFS is available in all OSes"
    },
    {
        "question": "Suppose a system uses linked list disk allocation. Which is the reason why we cannot have random access?",
        "answer": "Because it is impossible to know the location of nth block from the first block"
    },
    {
        "question": "A UNIX file system with the block size of 4KB; pointer size of 4 bytes; 12 direct pointers; 1 indirect pointer; 1 double indirect pointer; and 1 triple indirect pointer. Which is the maximum number of index blocks the system can use to create a file?",
        "answer": "3+1024*2+1024*1024"
    },
    {
        "question": "The disk partition is 500GB (1GB=1024MB, 1MB=1024KB, ...); the block size is 1KB. Suppose a system uses linked list disk allocation. Which is the suitable data type of the pointer (e.g. long)?",
        "answer": "int"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider a stable storage system, suppose the crash occurs during writing the second copy. Which is correct about the read protocol to recover the data?",
        "answer": "Second copy is bad, while the first copy is good, thus, replace the second with the first"
    },
    {
        "question": "A UNIX file system with the block size of 4KB; pointer size of 4 bytes; 12 direct pointers; 1 indirect pointer; 1 double indirect pointer; and 1 triple indirect pointer. Which is the maximum file size when the (single) indirect pointer is used?Which is the maximum file size when the (single) indirect pointer is used?",
        "answer": "(12+1024)*4 KB"
    }
]